<?xml version="1.0"?>
<databaseChangeLog xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-3.1.xsd">
  <changeSet author="roug" id="rev-1" context="demo" dbms="h2">
    <insert tableName="HLP_AREA">
      <column name="AREA_ID" value="Introduction"/>
      <column name="SCREEN_ID" value="Home_page"/>
      <column name="DESCRIPTION" value=""/>
      <column name="LANGUAGE" value=""/>
      <column name="HTML" value="&lt;h1&gt;What is ROD?&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; ROD is the EEA's reporting obligations database. It contains records describing environmental reporting obligations that countries have towards international organisations. &#9;ROD is part of Reportnet. Reportnet is group of web applications and processes developed by the EEA to support international environmental reporting. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;What are reporting obligations?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; Reporting obligations are requirements to provide information agreed between countries and international bodies such as the EEA or international conventions. Reporting obligations provide the basis for most environmental information flows.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;What does ROD cover?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; ROD includes all environmental reporting obligations that EEA member countries have towards DG environment, European marine conventions, Eurostat, OECD, UN, UNECE, as well as the EEA itself. To learn more about ROD, the status of the contents and the intended users, please check out the &lt;a href=&quot;documentation/Help&quot;&gt;general help&lt;/a&gt; section. &lt;/p&gt;"/>
      <column name="MD5" value=""/>
      <column name="POPUP_WIDTH" value="400"/>
      <column name="POPUP_LENGTH" value="400"/>
    </insert>
    <insert tableName="HLP_AREA">
      <column name="AREA_ID" value="Two_boxes"/>
      <column name="SCREEN_ID" value="Home_page"/>
      <column name="DESCRIPTION" value="The two boxes below the search form"/>
      <column name="LANGUAGE" value=""/>
      <column name="HTML" value="&lt;h2&gt;Latest news&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;11-May-11:&lt;/b&gt; You can now see what EEA products have been created with the data collected for an obligation. Example: &lt;a href=&quot;/obligations/616/products&quot;&gt;Natura 2000 sites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;05-May-11:&lt;/b&gt; We have implemented a new full-text search for the &amp;quot;Search ROD website&amp;quot; at the bottom of the front page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notifications:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to get an email when there is an approaching deadline, you can subscribe to notifications. You log into ROD, then click on the grey &lt;em&gt;Subscribe&lt;/em&gt; button on the left side. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For editors: We have implemented an Undo-functionality on obligations and instruments. If you need to undo an update, you click on the &amp;quot;Show history&amp;quot; button. &lt;/p&gt;"/>
      <column name="MD5" value=""/>
      <column name="POPUP_WIDTH" value="400"/>
      <column name="POPUP_LENGTH" value="400"/>
    </insert>
    <insert tableName="HLP_AREA">
      <column name="AREA_ID" value="Disclaimer"/>
      <column name="SCREEN_ID" value="documentation"/>
      <column name="DESCRIPTION" value="Disclaimer"/>
      <column name="LANGUAGE" value=""/>
      <column name="HTML" value="&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contents of the Reporting Obligations database are constantly under revision. The database exists, in part, because there is some uncertainty about the details of some reporting obligations that are themselves often under development and changing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each record in the database has been quality assessed by the EEA and partners. The status of a record is displayed in the record footer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Last updated: The last time when a record was updated.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Next update: The date when the next update is due.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Verified: The date on which the record was verified or quality assessed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Records that are verified are accepted as correct until the regular update cycle date is reached. If this information is not displayed in the footer, then the record has not been verified or quality assessed. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;ROD quality assurance processes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EEA makes use of thematic experts who are involved in environmental reporting to add content and update the database. The database was initially quality assessed in 2003, then updated. In 2003 and 2004 the database was extended to include new contents. The existing contents were updated in May/June 2004 and again in 2005. Updates to ROD are normally quality reviewed by EEA staff. Updating is usually carried out on an annual basis. Some records in ROD have been validated by the organisations that are responsible for the dataflows. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The database contains reporting obligations for EEA member countries as well as some other countries. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Material in the ROD is not necessarily comprehensive, complete, accurate or up to date and contains links to external sites over which the EEA has no control. The information in the database is supplied as is. You use it at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to keep the ROD timely and accurate. If errors are brought to our attention, we will correct them. If you notice something that you think is wrong. Please inform the helpdesk using the feedback link in the page footer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Detailed information about ROD contents management processes&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Quality assessment&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality Assessment is a one-off process to check the contents of ROD thematically. It was carried out in April of 2003. It confirmed that the contents (legislation, reporting obligations, reporting activities, links to guidelines and reporting organisations) are correct. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Updating is the regular process of reviewing the contents of the database to ensure that it is kept up-to-date. Updating is the review of legislative instruments and reporting obligations in ROD to check for information that is out-of-date or incorrect. This information is updated with the correct contents. Expert judgement is used to evaluate what the update cycle should be, i.e. when the contents should next be updated and this is noted for each record. It is also the process of identifying new reporting obligations that have been introduced since the database was last updated and need to be included in the database. These legislative references and reporting obligations are added to the database as part of updating. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Verification&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verification is a structured quality assurance process carried out by the EEA to quality control new coverage and new depth added to the database. Thematic experts carry out verification. Contents that are verified are accepted as correct until the regular update cycle date is reached. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Validation&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Validation is a quality assurance carried out by the 'owners' of information in the database in particular for non EEA / EIONET reporting obligations. Legislative authoritative bodies carry out validation for their own reporting obligations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;New coverage&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adding an increased level of detail to one of these subjects or adding coverage for other themes is adding new coverage for ROD. New information added to ROD is subsequently verified by thematic experts and enters an update cycle. &lt;/p&gt;"/>
      <column name="MD5" value=""/>
      <column name="POPUP_WIDTH" value="400"/>
      <column name="POPUP_LENGTH" value="400"/>
    </insert>
    <insert tableName="HLP_AREA">
      <column name="AREA_ID" value="Help"/>
      <column name="SCREEN_ID" value="documentation"/>
      <column name="DESCRIPTION" value="What is ROD"/>
      <column name="LANGUAGE" value=""/>
      <column name="HTML" value="&lt;h1&gt;What is ROD?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;ROD is the EEA's reporting obligations database. It contains records describing environmental reporting obligations that countries have towards international organisations. ROD is part of Reportnet. Reportnet is group of web applications and processes developed by the EEA to support international environmental reporting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What are reporting obligations?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reporting obligations are requirement to provide information agreed between countries and international bodies, such as the EEA or international conventions. Reporting obligations provide the basis for most environmental information flows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A reporting obligation is taken to mean any requirement to provide specified information to a secretariat, coordinating body or governing body of a legal instrument, or their representatives, whether or not there is a prescribed format or fixed frequency, or whether or not the word 'report' is used. Reporting obligations can be 'compulsory', 'expected' or 'voluntary' depending on whether information must be submitted in order to be in compliance with the legal instrument or is just submitted by countries at their own volition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What does ROD cover?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ROD includes all environmental reporting obligations that EEA member countries have towards the Environment DG, European marine conventions, Eurostat, OECD, UN, UNECE, As well as the EEA itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excluded from ROD are non-environmental reporting, requirements for proposals or the seeking of permits, requirements for specific actions to be taken (as opposed to reporting on actions taken), and administrative processes such as notifications of contact points, instances of issuance/withdrawal of permits (rather than reports that summarise permits issued), notifications of legal transposition and implementation measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why is ROD needed?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reporting obligations agreed between EU and international bodies and countries provide the framework for most environmental information flows. This framework has grown in Europe as reporting requirements for separate laws or sectors have been agreed to, often independently from one another. Duplication of efforts, together with a lack of a transparent, need-based approach to information flows, has contributed to poor response rates to many reporting obligations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ROD provides an overview inventory of reporting obligations. The database can be used to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;assist in the analysis of the reporting obligationss' burden of member countries;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;support member countries in planning and fulfilling reporting obligations;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;assist in streamlining the flow of data to the EEA and other international organisations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Who are ROD users?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rod is targeted towards three kinds of users:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;people involved in environmental policy development who are gathering information about an environmental issue (what information is reported where?);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;country representatives who are involved in environmental reporting (when is reporting due and what do I need to do?);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;people involved in environmental reporting from the perspective of the international organisations receiving and making use of the data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How is the information structured?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ROD database contains records at two levels. The upper level is the legislative instrument (LI) level. The lower level is the reporting obligation (RO) level. A legislative instrument record is the legal basis for one or more reporting obligations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How can I use ROD?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of the kind of questions that ROD can help answer and how to find the information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #993300&quot;&gt;Question:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;When does Italy next have to report waste statistics to Eurostat?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #006666&quot;&gt;Option 1:&lt;/span&gt; On the ROD front page &amp;gt; Deadlines &amp;gt; Italy &amp;gt; Advanced search &amp;gt; select 'Waste' from the issues list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #006666&quot;&gt;Option 2:&lt;/span&gt; On the ROD front page: select 'Italy' from the countries list, select 'Waste' from the issues list and 'Eurostat' from the reporting to list. Click on the 'Go' icon. Select the reporting obligation from the list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #993300&quot;&gt;Question:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What does Helcom collect information on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #006666&quot;&gt;Option:&lt;/span&gt; On the ROD front page: select 'Helcom' from the organisations list. Click on the 'Go' icon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #993300&quot;&gt;Question:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What do countries have to report on GMOs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #006666&quot;&gt;Option 1:&lt;/span&gt; On the ROD front page: select 'Various other issues' from the 'issues' list. Click on the 'Go' icon. Select links to the reporting obligations on GMOs from the list that appears.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #006666&quot;&gt;Option 2:&lt;/span&gt; Search the contents of ROD using Google for 'GMO'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #993300&quot;&gt;Question:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What are the current reporting guidelines for the UNFCCC greenhouse gas inventories?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold; color: #006666&quot;&gt;Option:&lt;/span&gt; On the ROD front page: select 'Climate change' form the issues list, select 'UNFCCC' from the organisations list. Click on the 'Go' icon. On the resulting list, click on the 'Greenhouse gas inventories' reporting obligation to open the reporting obligation record page. Check that the record is valid in the footer. Select the link to the reporting guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dates in ROD&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to specify reporting due dates in ROD: text based ('ASAP', etc.) and numeric date based.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Where possible numeric dates are used. This allows the deadlines to be sorted and used for notifications. If needed additional comments are added in the 'dates comments' field. In some instances numeric dates cannot be used, so a text deadline is used.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the numeric dates, the following guidelines are adhered to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reporting that is due in a year with no month or date specified is set as being due at on 31 December of the year. If the month is specified, then the reporting is set as being due on the last day in the month. The 'dates comments' field may be used to indicate this with text such as 'year only specified' or 'Year and month only specified' as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If reporting is due in time for a regular event, such as a three-yearly conference of the parties (COP) to a convention, then a numeric date for the COP is normally entered in the baseline date field, along with a frequency. A note in the 'date comments' field will indicate something similar to 'Reporting submitted prior to three yearly COP depending on exact dates of COP'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some calendar rounding is automatically done in this calculation for leap years and so on. Deadlines that have just passed are also shown for a brief period following their expiry. The ROD application recalculates the 'Next due date' fields for all obligations every day, so they are always up to date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where did the drive to create ROD come from?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive to create ROD came from several directions. The European Parliament and member country representatives to the EEA requested an overview of environmental reporting obligations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU's Sixth Environmental Action Programme recognized the need to revise the reporting system in order to achieve a clearer specification of policy-relevant information needs to increase transparency and to remove overlaps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The programme highlighted that solutions enabling a more transparent and efficient flow should be enabled, and that suitable IT developments should be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lastly the EEA itself makes use of ROD to identify and gain access to suitable datasets for use in its assessments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where can I get more information about ROD?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A FAQ is maintained by the Eionet Helpdesk at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://nmc.eionet.europa.eu/faq/&quot;&gt;http://nmc.eionet.europa.eu/faq/&lt;/a&gt;. If the FAQ does not answer your question then please contact the Helpdesk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presentation material and process documents to support ROD are available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://eea.eionet.europa.eu/Members/irc/eionet-circle/eionet-telematics/library?l=/reportnet/rod&quot;&gt;http://eea.eionet.europa.eu/Members/irc/eionet-circle/eionet-telematics/library?l=/reportnet/rod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A quick reference guide for ROD is available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detailed descriptions for each field in ROD can also be viewed by logged in users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;RSSHelp&quot;&gt;RSS XML/RPC data extraction help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;"/>
      <column name="MD5" value=""/>
      <column name="POPUP_WIDTH" value="400"/>
      <column name="POPUP_LENGTH" value="400"/>
    </insert>
    <insert tableName="HLP_AREA">
      <column name="AREA_ID" value="RSSHelp"/>
      <column name="SCREEN_ID" value="documentation"/>
      <column name="DESCRIPTION" value="RSS XML/RPC data extraction"/>
      <column name="LANGUAGE" value=""/>
      <column name="HTML" value="&lt;p&gt;The contents of ROD can be used in several different ways. Currently the main way is to browse the website. The contents of the database are also available for use as RSS, RDF and via XML-RPC. The purpose of this text is to give an introduction to how these technologies can be used to extract contents from ROD and overview what is available.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;RDF and RSS&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;RDF and RSS are methods of distributing links to content from web sites for others to use. There are a wide-range of web sites that 'syndicate' their content in this way.&lt;br /&gt;  ROD offers several RSS and RDF feeds for syndication. This allows distributed users to display selected custom content from ROD in their own website or in an application such as an RSS newsreader. The data is available in a variety of formats. Choose your preferred format and import the data on your website or your Intranet. There are no restrictions on the use of these feeds.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Please let us know, so that we can let you know if we plan to change the service in any way. Please click on the title below to get the corresponding feed.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;RSS (version 1.0)&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/events.rss&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reporting Obligation deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/events.rss&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/events.rss&lt;/a&gt;; lists all reporting obligations with their deadline linked to environmental issues or countries specified in the URL. Only obligations with a numeric date deadline are listed. This feed is used for the Eionet calendar.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss&quot;&gt;Reporting Obligations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss&lt;/a&gt;; lists all obligations linked to environmental issues or  countries specified in the URL.&lt;br /&gt;  Note: Use http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss?issues=[issueId1],[issueId2], etc. or  http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss?countries=[country1],[country2]  Example: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss?issues=8,9&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rss?issues=8,9&lt;/a&gt;. The issue IDs are: 1 - Climate Change, 2 - Ozone Depletion, 3 - Acidification, 4 - Soil, 6 - Air quality, 7 - Noise, 8 - Natural Resources, 10 - Chemicals, 12 - Various other issues, 13 - Waste, 14 - Biodiversity Change and Nature, 15 - Water.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/instruments.rss&quot;&gt;Legislative Instruments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/instruments.rss&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/instruments.rss&lt;/a&gt;; lists all legislative instruments.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;RDF&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations&quot;&gt;Reporting Obligations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rdf&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/obligations.rdf&lt;/a&gt;; lists all reporting obligations with linked countries and environmental issues&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/instruments&quot;&gt;Legislative Instruments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/instruments.rdf&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/instruments.rdf&lt;/a&gt;; lists all legislative Instruments.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/spatial&quot;&gt;Countries and territories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/spatial.rdf&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/spatial.rdf&lt;/a&gt;; lists all countries and territories.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;ROD XML-RPC&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In the context of ROD, XML-RPC can be used to look up records in the database across the Internet. It is not an open door to query the whole of ROD as the procedures must have been anticipated and developed and made available for calling over XML-RPC. There are currently five procedures available to users:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getActivities():&lt;/strong&gt; returns an ARRAY of STRUCTs that contains all the obligations in an ARRAY, with each obligation's information put into a STRUCT;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getROComplete():&lt;/strong&gt; returns an ARRAY of STRUCTs that contains all the obligations in an ARRAY, with each obligation's information put into a STRUCT; all the fields of the obligations are returned;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getROSummary():&lt;/strong&gt; returns an ARRAY of STRUCTs that contains all the obligations in an ARRAY, with each obligation's information put into a STRUCT; the STRUCT contains links to obligation, title, last update and description;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getRODeadlines():&lt;/strong&gt; returns an ARRAY of STRUCTs that contains all the obligations in an ARRAY, with each obligation's information put into a STRUCT; the STRUCT contains the reporting client name and the next deadline;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getCountries():&lt;/strong&gt; returns an ARRAY of STRUCTs that contains all countries from T_SPATIAL table; each STRUCT has got three country attributes:   &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;'ISO' - the two-letter ISO code in capitals;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;'URL' - '&lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/spatial/&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/spatial&lt;/a&gt;/&amp;lt;T_SPATIAL.PK_SPATIAL_ID&amp;gt;' [T_SPATIAL.PK_SPATIAL_ID];&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;'NAME'=[T_SPATIAL.SPATIAL_NAME].&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Other XML RPC methods can be put in place for key stakeholders if they specify what they want returned from ROD. If the returned information resembles the underlying logic for showing similar information on a web page then this can be fairly easy to implement. Sometimes all that is required is to do is to declare an existing method accessible over XML-RPC.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;To make use of the ROD XML RPC, it needs to be called from a program. The following is an example for the Python programming language:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;pre&gt;  import xmlrpclib&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  server = xmlrpclib.Server('http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/rpcrouter')&lt;br /&gt;  result = server.WebRODService.getActivities()&lt;br /&gt;  if not result:&lt;br /&gt;     print &amp;quot;No value returned&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;  else:&lt;br /&gt;     print result&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The ROD XML RPC Router is: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/rpcrouter&quot;&gt;http://rod.eionet.europa.eu/rpcrouter&lt;/a&gt;. The service name is: WebRODService.&lt;/p&gt;"/>
      <column name="MD5" value=""/>
      <column name="POPUP_WIDTH" value="400"/>
      <column name="POPUP_LENGTH" value="400"/>
    </insert>
  </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>
